(ｶｲｻﾞﾙ)陛下！ パレードへの参列を
お取りやめくださいませ｡
Your Majesty,
please do not attend the parade.
(ｼｬﾘｵｽ17世)
パレードは予定どおり行う｡
The parade will be carried out as scheduled.
悪魔どもが邪魔するなら➡
If the demons mean to interfere,
we will merely slaughter them all.
皆殺しにするまでだ｡
(ｱｻﾞｾﾞﾙ)なぜ来ない…｡
Why is she not coming?
(ｶｲｻﾞﾙ)悪魔たちが
何か たくらんでいる｡➡
The demons are scheming something.
正午には パレードの開始だ｡➡
The parade will commence at noon.
We have to find and stop them before then!
それまでに捜して
取り押さえなければ｡
ドカーン！
(ｱｻﾞｾﾞﾙ)
貴様 なぜ約束の場所に来ない？
Why did you not show up
where we were supposed to meet?
(ﾆｰﾅ･ﾄﾞﾗﾝｺﾞ)
だって パレード見てたんだもん｡
Because I was watching the parade!
とにかく来い！ もう時間がない！
Just come! We're out of time!
ここが 魔族どもとの
決戦の地ということだ｡
This is where we battle the demons.
ドォーン！
ドォン ドォン ドォン！
遅かったな｡
Finally.
It is time we settle this once and for all.
いいかげんに
決着をつけようではないか｡
(ｱｻﾞｾﾞﾙ)俺がヤツらを引き付ける｡
ドカッ！
I will draw them to me.
I want you to live!
(ｱｻﾞｾﾞﾙ)お前たちは生きろ！
ドゴン‼
Where did Mugaro go?
ムガロちゃん どこ行ったんだろ？
This way? That way?
こっち？ あっち？
ああ～ どっち？
Which way?
(ｶｲｻﾞﾙ)あれは…｡
Is that...
ムガロ｡
Mugaro!
So this is the power the gods seek.
これが 神の求める力か｡ あっ｡
(ｶｲｻﾞﾙ)陛下！
Your Majesty!
はあ～～！
ガキン！
Rage of Bahamut
なんのつもりだ？
What are you doing?
(ｶｲｻﾞﾙ)この戦いに
決着をつけてはなりません｡
This fight can't be settled like this.
余の命を
狙う悪魔を 逃せというのか？
Are you suggesting I let a demon
who is after my life go free?
貴様の戯れ言は もう聞き飽きた！
I am done listening to your nonsense!
I told you I would eliminate you
if you interfered.
邪魔をするなら
排除すると言ったはずだ｡
ドゴッ！
がはっ！
ぐっ があっ…｡
This demon will die if I defeat you!
お前が敗れれば
その悪魔は死ぬぞ｡
ドカッ！
うっ！
三種族の共存を
諦めないのだろう？
You still believe the three races can
live in peace, do you not?
Then try to fight for it here.
ならば この場を切り抜けてみよ！
ドスッ！
殺せ｡
Kill me.
戦いは終わった｡
終わってなどいない！
The fight is over.
It is not over!
今 この場で死ぬ意味は
ないはずだ｡
There should be no reason
for you to die here.
ムガロ！
あっ！
Mugaro!
ドサッ！
Your Majesty, are you injured?
(隊長)陛下 おケガは？
So they show themselves. Contemptible gods.
やはり現れたか 神め｡
Where are you going, Mugaro?
≫どこ行くの!? ムガロちゃん｡
Turn into a dragon!
(ｱｻﾞｾﾞﾙ)竜になれ！
えっ？
ニーナ 竜になるんだ！
Nina!
You have to transform!
竜って…｡ 何？ 急に｡
What? What are you saying?
We need your power now!
今こそ お前の力が必要なんだ｡➡
ムガロを…➡
You have to save Mugaro!
俺たち魔族を助けてくれ！
You have to save the demons!
ダメ 無理！ 変身できない！
It's not working! I can't transform!
な… 何よ？
What?
ガン！
うっ！
Damn it all!
(ｱｻﾞｾﾞﾙ)ちくしょう～～～‼
Rage of Bahamut
The Rag Demon has finally been caught!
(市民)包帯悪魔
とうとう捕まったか｡
(市民)
さすがは シャリオス様だな｡
King Charioce did it!
(市民)
それにしても 騎士団の団長が➡
I can't believe a knight captain
was aiding the demons.
悪魔に加担してたなんて
とんでもねぇな｡
(市民)オルレアン騎士団ってのも
落ちたもんだ｡
How far the Orleans Knights have fallen.
(市民)
私 この団長 見かけたことあるよ｡
I've seen the captain before.
兵隊さん
このニーナって子は 間違いだ｡
Sir, there's gotta be some sort of mistake
with this girl Nina.
こんな大層なことが
できる子じゃあねぇ｡
She's not someone who could do anything
like this!
そうだよ｡ ニーナは いつも元気で
とってもいい子なんだよ！
That's right! Nina's such a good,
cheerful girl.
Yeah!
そうだ そうだ！
(ﾊﾟﾝ屋)昨日だって➡
When I put her on my shoulders yesterday
so she could see the parade better,
俺が肩車して
パレードを見せてやったら➡
きゃっきゃと喜んでたんだ｡
she was so happy.
There's no way she attacked the king after that.
あのあとに
王様を襲ったなんて ありえねぇ｡
なあ 頼むよ｡
兵隊さんから もう一度➡
Please, could you talk to the king
and ask him to look into it one more time?
王様に調べるように言ってくれ…｡
おっ…｡
If you defend this traitor any more,
(兵士)
それ以上 反逆者をかばうなら➡
I'll throw you all into prison too!
貴様らも牢にぶち込むぞ！
What did they do?
(ﾘﾀ)何やってんのよ あの子たち｡
The drunk and the duck
have run off too.
酔っ払いとアヒルも
どっか行っちゃうし｡
I will now read the charges.
(重臣)
これより 罪状を読み上げる｡➡
｢被告人 カイザル･リドファルド｡
被告は 陛下を守護する➡
First, the accused, Kaisar Lidfard.
You have been accused of consorting with demons
オルレアン騎士団長でありながら
悪魔と密会を行うこと数度｡➡
while having sworn to protect His Majesty
as captain of the Orleans Knights.
パレードにおいては
反逆者たちの蛮行に加担｡➡
You aided the rebels with their attack on the parade,
and together with the Rag Demon,
raised your sword against His Majesty,
包帯悪魔と共に
陛下へ刃を向ける暴挙には➡
もはや 弁解の余地なし｡➡
for which there can be no justification!
-These are crimes against the sovereign.
-What did he want to do?
国家への犯意ありとみなし｣…｡
(ｱﾚｻﾝﾄﾞ)あの人➡
一体 何がしたかったんすかね？
(重臣)｢国家反逆罪を適用する｣！
And you are hereby charged with treason!
It's no use. I'm not getting excited at all.
(心の声)
≪ダメだ ドキドキしない≫
The accused, Nina Drango.
(重臣)｢被告人 ニーナ･ドランゴ｣｡
えっ？
(重臣)｢被告人は 人でありながら
悪魔の危険思想に染まり➡
You are accused of sympathizing with
dangerous demon ideology despite being human,
パレードにおいての襲撃に加担｡➡
and, additionally, aiding in the parade attacks.
また ここ数日のうちに
現れたとされる➡
There are also suspicions of your connection
with a red dragon
that has emerged in the last few days,
赤い竜との関係性も疑わしく➡
反乱分子であることは
明白である｡➡
and it is evident you are a member of the rebellion.
よって 被告人にも
国家反逆罪を適用する｣！
Therefore, you will also
be charged with treason!
陛下 判決をお願いいたします｡
Your Majesty, your judgment, please.
お願いします｡
Please.
Imprison both in the prison tower,
両名を牢獄島において
無期の刑に処する｡
where they will be held indefinitely.
えっ!? 無期？
What? Indefinitely?
Take them away!
連れていけ！
えっ ちょ… やだ｡
待って 待って 待って 待って！
What? No! Wait, wait, wait!
無期って… うそ！
Indefinitely? You've gotta be kidding!
Could you make it more like three days?
３日くらいにして｡
Indefinitely is way too harsh.
無期って あんまりだよ～｡
うっ！
待て｡
Wait.
What are you looking at?
何見てんのよ｡
言っとくけど 私 あんたのこと➡
Just so you know,
I don't think you're a good king or anything.
全然 いい王様だなんて
思ってないんだから｡
王様は みんなに優しくしなきゃ
いけないんじゃないの？
Doesn't the king have to be nice to everyone?
Picking on folks because they're demons,
putting collars on them,
悪魔だからって
いじめて 首輪なんか着けて➡
hurting them to make them do what you say-
言うこと聞かせようと
傷つけたりして！
do you really think that's okay?
そんなことしていいと
思ってるの!? うっ…｡
王都の工事だって
悪魔に手伝ってもらってるくせに➡
When this whole capital was built by demons!
本当は 悪魔の力が必要なくせに➡
When actually you need them!
How could you just kill them
without a thought?
簡単に殺そうとするなんて！
あなたのやってることは
ただの弱い者いじめよ！
You're nothing but a big bully!
みんなは あなたのこと➡
Everyone says you're a great king
who made the capital rich,
王都を繁栄させた
偉大な王様だって言うけど➡
but it's all a lie!
そんなのうそ！
あんたは ただの悪い王様だ！
You're just an evil king!
A worthless king who just sits on his throne,
picking on the weak demons!
弱い悪魔をいじめて
威張って ふんぞり返ってる➡
ダメな王様だ！
(兵士)ぐっ｡
Humans and demons may be scared of you,
人も悪魔も あなたにおびえて
怖がってるけど➡
私は 違う｡
but not me!
I'm not the least bit scared of you!
あんたなんか
ち～っとも怖くないんだから！
何笑ってんのよ｡
(兵士)くっ… いいかげん 黙れ｡
What are you laughing at?
Shut your mouth al-
ああっ！ あ痛たたたっ！ ああっ｡
Are you the red dragon?
お前は
赤い竜なのか？
No. I have no idea what you're referring to.
違います｡
何をおっしゃっているのか➡
分かりません｡
連れていけ｡
Take them away.
(兵士)立て！
やめて｡
-Get up!
-Stop!
-Come on!
-That hurts!
(兵士)ほら｡
痛い！
Lady Gabriel.
(ｿﾌｨｴﾙ)ガブリエル様
気が付いたようです｡
The child is awake.
(ｶﾞﾌﾞﾘｴﾙ)
おびえることはありません｡➡
There is nothing to fear.
The gods here
ここにいる神たちは➡
are all on your side.
皆 あなたの仲間なのですよ｡
Your name is El.
あなたの名前は エル｡➡
あなたの母ジャンヌ･ダルクが
あなたに授けた名前です｡
It is the name your mother Jeanne D'Arc
gave you.
お母さんに
会いたくはないですか？
Do you not wish to see your mother?
Do you not wish to save your mother?
お母さんを
助けたくはないですか？
私たちと力を合わせれば➡
If you join forces with us,
お母さんに会うことができますよ｡
you will be able to meet your mother.
(ﾊﾝｻ)クワッ！ クワァ～｡➡
クワァ～！
ドン！ ドンドン！
(ﾊﾝｻ)クワァ～！
≫(ﾊﾞｯｶｽ)やめとけ｡
Forget it.
Why'd we have to return to heaven this way?
(ﾊﾝｻ)こんな形で
神の国に戻ってくるなんて！➡
あのとき ソフィエル様に➡
We should have told Lady Sofiel about Mugaro
when we had the chance.
ムガロのことを
言えばよかったんですよ！
(ﾊﾞｯｶｽ)ふんっ｡
≪(ｿﾌｨｴﾙ)ハンサの言うとおりだ｡
Hamsa is right.
ソフィエル様！ どうクワァ
私たちの軟禁をお解きください｡➡
Lady Sofiel! Please let us free!
We planned to tell you that this was the child you
were seeking once we gathered enough evidence!
あの少年が例の子供であると➡
十分な証拠を得てから
伝えるつもりだったのです｡➡
決して
謀反の意志などございません！
I assure you we had no intention of betraying you.
(ｿﾌｨｴﾙ)なぜ あの子供を隠した？
Why did you hide the child?
Answer me.
答えろ！
クワァ～…｡ クワッ!?
I just felt like it.
なんとなくだ｡
(ｿﾌｨｴﾙ)なんとなく？
You just felt like it?
What do you mean by that?
どういう意味だ？
(ﾊﾞｯｶｽ)意味なんてねぇよ｡
There's no meaning.
(ｿﾌｨｴﾙ)バカなのか お前は｡
(ﾊﾝｻ)ほんとにバカです！
Are you a fool?
He really is!
And what are you looking to start with that kid?
(ﾊﾞｯｶｽ)
お前らこそ あのガキを使って➡
何を始める気だ？
Humans have lost their way,
(ｿﾌｨｴﾙ)ガブリエル様は
信仰心を失った人間たちが➡
and Lady Gabriel wishes to guide them
back to offering their prayers to the gods.
再び 神のみもとに
祈りをささげるよう➡
導くことをお考えだ｡
And you'll be using the kid for that?
(ﾊﾞｯｶｽ)
それに あいつを利用するのか？
The child's power is the only thing capable of
breaking the forbidden magic used by humans.
あの子供の力は➡
人間たちが使う
禁じられた術を破る唯一の力だ｡
(ﾊﾞｯｶｽ)くっ｡
あんな子供を巻き込むな！➡
Leave the kid out of this!
It'll be Jeanne D'Arc all over again.
ジャンヌ･ダルクの
二の舞になるぞ｡
You overstep your bounds.
口が過ぎるぞ｡
(ﾊﾝｻ)クワァ～…｡
も… 申し訳ございません
ソフィエル様｡
A thousand apologies, Lady Sofiel.
酒がないもので
ちょっとイライラしてるんです｡
He's just a little irritated
because he hasn't had his drink.
(ｿﾌｨｴﾙ)お前たちが 任務を
妨害したことに変わりはない｡➡
The fact remains that you interfered with our mission.
しばらく ここで頭を冷やせ｡
You would do well to think about
what you've done here.
クワァ…｡
Why is this happening to us?
我々は なんという
運命なんでしょうクワァ？➡
Maybe you backed the humans too much on this one.
人に肩入れし過ぎたんじゃ
ないですクワァ？
Shut up.
うるせぇ｡
(ﾊﾝｻ)そういえば➡
That reminds me. When we were teleporting away
私たちが魔法陣に消えるとき➡
the young lady was yelling from below.
地上で
お嬢さんが叫んでましたね｡
I wonder what's happened to her.
(ﾊﾝｻ)どうしてますクワァね｡➡
I hope she's okay...
無事だといいんですけど…｡
(船頭)ほ～ら 見えてきたぞ｡
あれが お前の新居だ｡➡
You can see it now.
That's your new home.
なかなか立派だろう？➡
Pretty nice, isn't it?
脱出不可能な
難攻不落の地下牢獄なんだぜ？
It's an impregnable and unescapable
underground dungeon.
おじさん 包帯悪魔はどうしたの？
Hey, what happened to the Rag Demon?
(船頭)ああ～ 今頃は たっぷりと
拷問を受けてるだろうよ｡➡
Probably getting tortured as we speak.
Trying to get him to spill about who else
is working with him.
他に仲間がいないか
吐かせるためにな｡
えっ…｡
(船頭)おい｡➡
Hey, don't talk to the prisoners.
罪人と口を利くなよ！
あっ!?➡
いいだろ｡ 誰も見てねぇし
かまわねぇだろ｡➡
Who cares? Nobody's even around!
You're always getting worked up about nothing.
おめぇ いっつも細けぇんだよ｡
≪ごめんね アザゼル≫
I'm sorry, Azazel.
≪あのとき
私が竜になれていたら…≫
If only I was able to transform into a dragon, then...
バチン！(ﾑﾁでたたく音)
(ｱｻﾞｾﾞﾙ)ああっ…｡
Just spill it already!
いいかげん 吐いたらどうだ？
おりゃあ～！
Tell me where your base is!
(兵士)アジトの場所を言え！➡
おりゃあ～！➡
ひひひひっ｡ あっ｡
≪コツ コツ コツ…(足音)
How unsightly.
ぶざまだな｡
お前は
あの神が連れ去った子供が➡
Did you know what the taken child was?
何者か知っていたのか？
You really had no idea.
知らずに連れ歩いていたのか｡
What a fool.
まぬけなヤツだ｡
(囚人)ひ～っひひひっ｡
(囚人)なんだよ｡ ええっ？
(囚人)見るな｡
(囚人)なんだよ｡
うっ！ 痛たたっ…｡
The gods were desperate to get the child.
あの子供を手に入れるために➡
神は 躍起になっていた｡
神の手に渡る前に
殺すつもりだったが➡
I planned to kill the child
before he fell into their hands,
but you ruined it all.
お前たちのせいで台なしだ｡
まあいい｡ あの子供を手に入れ➡
No matter.
The gods are overconfident now that they
have the child. So I will simply kill them all.
調子に乗った神もろとも
亡き者にしてやる｡
When I do,
そうすれば さすがに
あの女も祈ることをやめるだろう｡
that woman will surely stop praying.
That woman...
｢あの女｣？
The former saint...
かつての聖女➡
ジャンヌ･ダルクだ｡
Jeanne...
D'Arc.
It's okay, it's okay
I cast the usual spell
Stagnation, stagnation
My words and heart are at odds
Default
I've taken all the paint
And mixed up all the colors
Until you're left with me
So fragile
Yet strong
Close to overflowing
But not spilling
Because I'm incomplete
I won't amount to much
This is just a good luck charm
I'm not asking for your help
I was just clinging to you
Let's end it all today
I'm done living this pointless life
I've taken my last, pointless breath
To whom it may concern, see ya and goodbye
I killed the person I was yesterday
A new morning is coming
Get in there!
(看守)さっさと入れ！
(ｶｲｻﾞﾙ)うわっ あたっ！
ガシャン
Do you really have to be so rough?
もっと ましな扱いは
できないのか！
Honestly!
ったく…｡
≪これは また
とんだ騎士様のご登場だ｡➡
Well, well. If it isn't the great and noble knight,
gracing us with his presence.
≪もっと周りを見ろって
いつも言ってんだろ｡
I keep telling you to pay more attention
to your surroundings, don't I?
Hey.
- It's the aristocrat, Kaisar!
- Demon Azazel here!
- I challenge you to a battle!
- Bring it on!
Next time on Rage of Bahamut:
Virgin Soul, "Same Old. Same Old."
- Ready!
- Rock, Paper!
- R-r-ro-rock!
- Hey!
Baha Soul!!
Baha Baha Bahasoul.
You there.
You must watch next time too, understood?